vitacostrewards.com 2018-09-08

# Privacy Policy | Vitacost.com

####  Effective on: (03/01/2017) 

Vitacost is committed to your privacy. This notice serves to help you better understand what information Vitacost collects, how it uses that information, and with whom Vitacost may share a limited portion of that information. The most recent version of Vitacost's privacy policy can be found on this page (http://www.vitacost.com/privacy). If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you should contact  Customer Support by email. 

Vitacost knows that you value your personal information, and we protect your privacy as if it were our own. Vitacost's uses of your information are limited to the ways outlined in this notice, except as required by law and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website. 

  1. What kind of information about me does Vitacost collect? 
  2. How does Vitacost use this information? 
  3. What information can I access or modify? 
  4. How does Vitacost secure my information? 
  5. Can I opt-out? 

####  What kind of information about me does Vitacost collect? 

Vitacost collects information about you in these ways: 

1\.  Order information you give us:  If you place an online order, our secure order form requests contact, billing, and financial information (such as your credit card numbers for purchases). Contact information from the order form (email address, name, billing and shipping address, and phone number) is used to send orders and information about our company to you. 

Types of Information We Collect 

  * Your name
  * Your billing and delivery address
  * Your e-mail address 
  * Your phone (or mobile) number 
  * Your credit/debit card number 
  * Information on how you are using the Sites 
  * Your purchase/return/exchange information 

We Collect Information When 

  * You purchase, order, return, exchange or request information about our products and services from the Sites or mobile applications.
  * You create an Vitacost.com account.
  * You connect with us regarding customer service via our customer service center, or on social media platforms. 
  * You visit the Sites or participate in interactive features of the Sites or mobile applications. 
  * You use a social media service, for example, our Blog, Facebook page or YouTube channel. 
  * You sign up for e-mails, mobile messages, or social media notifications from us. 
  * You enter a contest or sweepstakes, respond to one of our surveys, or participate in a focus group. 
  * You provide us with comments, suggestions, or other input. 
  * You interact with Vitacost.com through your computer, tablet or mobile device

Account information:  If you choose to create a Vitacost account, your login information is stored with any other information you associate with your account.

2\.  Technologies Used: We may use tracking pixels/web beacons, cookies and or other technologies to receive and store certain types of information. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser information, Internet Service Provider (ISP), operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data. This information helps us customize your website experience and make our marketing messages more relevant. It also allows us to provide features such as storage of items in your cart between visits. This includes our content presented on other websites or mobile applications. In order to provide the best customer experience possible, we also use this information for reporting and analysis purposes, such as how you are shopping our website, performance of our marketing efforts, and your response to those marketing efforts. 

3\.  Non-personal information we receive automatically: Like most websites, Vitacost utilizes cookies. Cookies are a mechanism to remember information about you when you navigate from one web page to another. Our website uses cookies to hold a user's unique session identifiers, allowing us to serve correct information back to the user. Such information includes your shopping cart items, or whether you are logged in. Our website cookies do not hold any personally identifiable information. Vitacost may use other similar technologies which allow us to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visit to help us better your experience. 

4\.  Third Party Cookies:  We allow third-party companies to collect non-personally identifiable information when you visit the Sites and to use that information to serve ads for our products or services or for products or services of other companies when you visit the Sites or other websites. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., navigational, click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, etc.) during your visits to the Sites and other websites in order to provide advertisements about our goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These parties may use a cookie or a third party web beacon, or other technologies, to collect this information. 

5\.  Mobile information:  When you utilize our iPhone® or Android® phone apps, we may receive non-personally identifiable information, such as a unique identifier for your device letting us know what type of phone you are using. 

####  How does Vitacost use this information? 

Vitacost uses information collected in these ways: 

1\.  Order processing and customer service  After placing an online order, your contact information including your email address will be used to get in touch with you should we have questions regarding your order or should we need to notify you of the status of your order. Your credit card information is transmitted securely to our third party processing provider in compliance with Payment Card Industry standards. You will automatically be registered to receive our email newsletter, which you are able to opt out of at any time by accessing your user account, following the unsubscribe link found in the email newsletter, or sending an email to newsletter@vitacost.com with the word UNSUBSCRIBE followed by your email address in the subject of the email (example: UNSUBSCRIBE youremail@emailaddress.com). 

2\.  Third-party service providers:  Vitacost works closely with other companies and individuals to facilitate transactions and better your experience. Examples of third-party service provider services include shipping orders, analyzing data, providing accurate search results and links, processing credit card payments, affiliate marketing, and newsletters. Any information that Vitacost shares with a third-party service provider is done so safely, securely, and under a contractual relationship with that provider to protect your data.

3\.  Promotional offers:  From time to time we or a service provider acting on our behalf may use your name, email address, and/or mailing address to send you an offer for a Vitacost product or service we believe to be of interest to you.

4\.  Other information you provide us:  Information you provide us for specific offers or services is only used for the limited purpose for which the information is being given. Examples of these offers or services include Refer-A-Friend, Email to a Friend, surveys, and sweepstakes.

####  What information can I access or modify? 

If you are a registered customer, you may log into your account and view or modify the account information on file, including personally identifiable information, recent orders, payment settings, shopping lists, and Set & Save settings. In order to protect your personal information, only the last four numbers of any saved credit cards are viewable.

####  How does Vitacost secure my information? 

Vitacost utilizes technologies including Transport Layer Security (TLS) and database encryption to ensure the privacy of your personal information. When you make an online purchase, our advanced security technology uses strong secure protocols to send your personal data to us. To further protect your information, we utilize state of the art back-end security systems, encryption technologies and restrict employee access to your information. Any time we share your information with a third party consistent with this Privacy Policy, we utilize technological and contractual safeguards to keep your information safe. 

Vitacost.com is PCI DSS 3.2 Compliant and regularly participates in multiple audits a year to ensure our environment is continually secure.

While we are confident ordering online is safe and secure, if for any reason you cannot access the secure server or feel uncomfortable ordering online, please feel free to place your order with us by phone at 1-800-381-0759. As a general practice, it is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. If using a shared computer, be sure to log out of your account prior to leaving the computer. 

####  Can I opt-out? 

Email and Promotional:  At any time you can adjust your [communication preferences](https://www.vitacost.com/MyAccount/ManageCommunications.aspx), including opting out of promotional mailings, from within your Vitacost account. You also have the right to disable your account. To do so, you may call or email  Customer Service.

Third Party Cookies: To opt-out of third-party vendor's cookies on other websites, visit the Network Advertising Initiative website, [click here.](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)

The Adobe Marketing Cloud Device Co-op: Vitacost participates in the The Adobe Marketing Cloud Device Co-op to better understand how you use our website and apps across the various devices you use, and to deliver tailored promotions. [Learn more](https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com/) about how Adobe does this. 

####  EU and Swiss CUSTOMER PRIVACY 

  * Vitacost.com is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).
  * In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU or Swiss individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield or the Swiss-US Privacy Shield, Vitacost.com is potentially liable.
  * Any information you provide us is controlled and processed by Vitacost.com, Inc., 5400 Broken Sound Blvd Suite 500, Boca Raton, FL 33487, USA. 
  * We comply with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. We have certified to the Department of Commerce that we adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.
  * Pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield and the US-Swiss Privacy Shield, Vitacost.com acknowledges that EU and Swiss individuals have the right to access the personal information that we maintain about them. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should contact us directly using one of the following methods: 
    * Send an e-mail to [CustomerSupport@vitacost.com](mailto:CustomerSupport@vitacost.com)
    * Call our Customer Care line at 1-800-381-0759
    * Write us at Vitacost.com, Attention: Customer Support   
5400 Broken Sound Blvd Suite 500, Boca Raton, FL 33487 USA
  * We will provide an individual opt-out choice before we share their data with third parties other than our agents, or before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, you may submit a written request to [CustomerSupport@vitacost.com](mailto:CustomerSupport@vitacost.com)
  * Note that we may be required to share personal data of EU and Swiss individuals in response to lawful requests by public authorities including to meet national security and law enforcement requirements.
  * In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Vitacost.com commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy should first contact us using one of the following methods: 
    * Send an e-mail to [CustomerSupport@vitacost.com](mailto:CustomerSupport@vitacost.com)
    * Call our Customer Care line at 1-800-381-0759
    * Write us at Vitacost.com, Attention: Customer Support   
5400 Broken Sound Blvd Suite 500, Boca Raton, FL 33487 USA
  * We have further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/> for more information and to file a complaint.
  * Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.
